MY FIRST JOB AWAY FROM HOME
I was 8 years old 

Those were the happy days of my childhood when I could play around my parental home. That didn't last long for in the year 1863, I was then eight years old, I could begin to tend cows. My father hired me out to a man by the name of Handrop. I should have two dollars for the first summer and a pair of wooden shoes. I would herd cows in the grove. Now my trouble began. In Denmark the days are very long in the summer and very warm. There are also some big cow flies and they would bother the cows so they would stampede and I would run for dear life to herd them so they should not get into damage. I would cry and run and run and cry. I thought of my dear mother and sister and my little brother and of the happy days I used to have and wished myself home again. But it was no use, I had to stay. Summer went and winter came. Then I should go to school. That went all right to begin with but it wasn't long until the children knew I was a Mormon boy, and nearly all the school children hated me. Even the teacher could hate and if he could get half a chance he would punish me more than the rest because I was a Mormon boy. I would tell my mother at night when I got home. She would console me by saying, "You do not need to care for that, they will soon stop and the time will soon come when we will get of Babylon and go home to Zion." 

Soon it was spring again. I was then hired for a year to the same man and my wages were double. That is, the money part, and I should go to school two days a week in the winter; but I had no time to study as I was busy with my work. My lessons were neglected and I would catch it from the teacher and he would say, "I'll learn you, Mormon." When I had a spare moment would run home to mother to be comforted as she lived only a littIe way from the place where I stayed. Thus I spent that and the next year with the same man. My sister worked for the same man the next year. That made it a little better for me. 

In the year 1865, in the last part of the year, Handrop hung himself. It put an end to my working for him. My father then hired me out to another man and I should have twelve dollars which is the same as six dollars in American money. Now my schooling was ended and it was a limited one. I could scarcely write my own name. The new folks seemed to be very nice for a few days, 'but I soon found I had been deceived. I should go to school one day a week but that was stopped. I had too much work to tend eleven cows and many other chores. He also had a hired man working for him who would work with the team. I was sometimes so tired that I could not sleep at night. Now I had no mother to run and see for she had moved to the city of Aarhus, as father had his work there and mother did the housekeeping for the missionaries. So I had to bear my burden. If I made any complaint I would get a slap side the head by the man I worked 

