OUR FATHER'S HISTORY 

This book has been copied just as Father wrote it up to the time he came from his mission. Not one word has been added or taken away. The last paragraph was written by his eldest daughter. In addition, each one of his children has added his memories of Father and Mother. It has been compiled and made into book form by one of his children for the sole purpose of bettering our lives and that our children may know their grandparents. Even though we are older and most of us have grown families, we can read over the writings of Father and gain inspiration and guidance for our everyday lives. It will give all who read it a better understanding of the truthfulness of all things and desire to do better each day we live. Our hearts are full of gratitude for having such choice people for our parents. Our heritage is great and through this blessing our efforts and accomplishments, if we live right, should be unlimited. 

This book has been written in the plain, simple language of a great man, our Father. 

