and sister was great; but there was still one left whom I loved as dearly as those who had gone before us. He had no excuse so far as the Gospel was concerned because father had taught him that for years and he was now a married man and was able to judge for himself. On the 21st of June 1872, I bade my brother goodbye. It was a sad moment. After I had said good-bye I ran on the ship and stood behind a mast. The last sight of my brother was with his arms clasped around father's neck. Both of them were crying. I remember the Saints sang the old farewell song, "Tell Babylon, Tell Babylon, We Say Farewell". It was not long till we were out of sight. 

ON THE WATER 

Next day we arrived at Kjahenhaven [Kjobenhaven]. There we stopped a day at some hotel. I remember that I went down on the street and stood looking at the many people as they went past. Among them were two boys. They asked me if I was a Mormon. "Yes", was my reply. One of the boys had a shovel handle which he struck me with. I fell to the ground. I do not remember how long I lay there but when I got up I was very sick. I did not get over it for several days. I was sick all the way to England and the sea made me more sick. We stopped in England one day and I got a little rest, but when we got out on the Atlantic I was sicker than ever. It was the regular sea-sickness. The first two days, I ate a little but the next nine days I was so sick I could not eat at all. One' day, my father came down and told me the ship had sprung a leak and that I would have to try to get up. I told him it could not sink too soon to suit me, just so I could get out of my misery. They got the leak stopped and the next day I heard someone talk about land. I thought I would try to get up and see if there was any of it. I was so weak that i had to sent for my father to help me up. The sea was calm and everybody was enjoying himself. As I stood gazing over the mighty deep I got to feeling hungry. I looked around from where I stood and saw a stove pot standing by' the kitchen door. It had a little warm rice mush in it. I asked a man if I could have it. He kindly came and took 'me by the hand and sat me down in a corner and gave me a spoon and a little butter and told me to eat, and 'I did. I felt well·after it and I got up and stood a little while and then went down to my berth. I went to sleep and did not awake until next morning when I was awakened by shouts of "Land in sight!" I jumped up, seemingly well, and got up on deck and ran over to the front end of the ship and stood there looking at the various fish until we arrived in the harbor of New York. I must say my joy was great! The first thing I asked father for was a little milk. He went and got me a pint which I drank all at once and I began to eat a little although I was very weak. 

OUR FAMILY REUNION 

We now had the long trip on the train to Salt Lake City before 

