A SHORT SKETCH OF MY LIFE 

by William Sorensen 

I was born of goodly parents on the 9th day of November in the year of our Lord, 1855, in Denmark, in a place called Hallemslex [Hallenslev] Saby Sogen Hallaksmt [Holbækamt]. 

My father, Na Hans Sorensen, was born the 30th day of September, 1825. My mother, Na Ane Neilsdatter, was born the 25th day of December, 1822. Both of them were baptized on the 5th day of February, 1858,. by Elder O. Poulsen. Father was confirmed a member of the church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints on the 14th of February, 1858, by Elder A. Anderson. Mother was confirmed on the 16th of February, 1858, by Elder O. Poulsen. 

My father was a weaver by trade and he was very poor and when he obeyed the Gospel, the people where he then lived got angry at him and would not support him with their work, so he was forced to leave that place. He then moved his family to Jylland to the city of Aarhus in the year 1858 and got work as a stone cutter. He rented a little place about six miles from the city where we could keep a cow and a few chickens. He moved his family out there, which consisted of five, mother and four children.' Our new home was called Mosgaard Hus. We were now quite comfortable and father had to go to his work again, but that was all right with us children. We could have all the bread and milk we could eat, but it was a little different with mother. She had to be alone and care for us, and tend the chores, but she together wit:h father would work with love to support us, and were happy to know they were members of the Church of Christ and that they had a testimony of the same and that they could live in peace. 

I was then four years old. I remember my mother would go out gleaning wheat and rye in the summer. She would take a sack and my little sister on her arm and the rest of us would catch hold of her dress and when evening came we would toddle off for home. Though tired of packing her burden, Ma would get us some bread and milk and we would play around the house and gladden the heart of a loving mother. 

Since father was off to work yet, I was now so big I could help Ma a little with the cow and other things. My little sister was now four years old, I six, and we had no baby; but on the 11th of July, 1962, we had a brother brought to us and he was made welcome by all of us. I was now the middle one of five. Now we were too many to stay home and my brother and elder sister had to work out and I was left to help Mama with the little ones and in the winter I would go to school. 

