for. Soon the other boy left and then he, the man, asked me to take the team and haul some rocks. I did so and one day as I was gathering rocks, a bird came flying and scared the horses and of course they ran away and broke the wagon and harness and kicked each other quite bad. Of course, I expected he would nearly kill me. We ran to catch then and when we got then I ran for the house. His wife then came out and when he made for me to give me a thrashing she jumped between us and told him to strike her. Thus I was delivered from his clutches that time. I stayed there two years and endured many hardships. 

When my time was up my father came to take me home to help him cut rocks and I was glad of it. Mr. Willerson then offered to double my wages but father thought I could do more good at home. His family was still in the office. I rested for a few days and then began my new work. I had a good father and would do all in my power to learn how to handle the hammer. In the evenings I could go home and see my dear mother. That was a treat for me and I could also have a chance to read and write both Danish and English as we had Brother J. Howgaard for President and he was willing to teach us. That did not last long. Soon we, Father and I, and his man, went to Sans So to work and we would be gone for months at a time. I was now in my 13th year, it being 1868. We would work late and early to try to get enough .money to go to Zion, but it seemed to be impossible and sometimes father and I would get disheartened. Thus we worked three years. 

AMERICA ... HERE WE COME 

In 1870 my elder sister got helped out. [She left Denmark and came to America.] In 1871 the Lord opened the way so that my mother and younger sister and brother got off. Now Father and I were left to fight our way through the best way we could. My eldest brother was married but he could not see that the Gospel was true. He was a good man and I loved him as I did the rest of the family and I would go and see him when I could and it would cheer me up a little for all my plans were to work hard every day. Brother P. Madsen was then President, and he promised me in the name of Jesus, if I would be faithful, that the Lord would open the way for Father and me next year and that when I got to Zion I would be blessed a hundred fold. My father was not so strong as he might be. I sometimes thought I had a hard lot and I was the middle one of five which seemed to me to be the unlucky one. There was nothing else to do but work. A year went by and it was a hard one. Father and I would get up in the morning as soon as we could see and kept on until it was dark at night; but the time went and in the month of June 1872, our deliverance came for me and Father to go home to Zion, to the place where God has said that his people should gather. 

Though I did not know the Gospel was true, I believed it with all my heart and the thought of soon seeing my dear Mother, brother 

